如果你想有参考资料的话  可以打开开发者API指南中的设置部分
Open up the Developer API Guide for Settings, if you want to follow along.
如果你经过仔细考虑后  你依然决定要把它加为一个设置项
If you've pondered it carefully and you've decided you really want this to
下面就是你需要做的  Android提供一种分层级显示
be a setting, this is what you do next. Android provides a way to display
偏好设置的方法  包括设置的分类标题  比如这里显示的这个
a hierarchy of preferences, including headers, such as the ones shown here.
偏好设置的值被称为设置概述  就是这里看到的
The value of the preference is called the preference summary, and that's seen
它看上去很像一个副标题  设置选项会提供UI界面
here. It looks almost like the subtitle text. The preference also provides UI.
这样用户就可以更改设置了  你只需要提供设置概述的文字信息
To allow users to modify that setting. You just need to supply the strings, but
并不需要实现像这里的Spinner控件一样的UI界面
you don't have to implement the UI like the spinner here.
常见的设置类型包括CheckBox型设置  List列表型设置
Common preference types are the CheckBoxPreference, ListPreference,
还有EditText型设置  我们可以在系统的设置应用下的开发者选项里看到
EditTextPreference. We can see some examples in the settings app under
一些例子  这些都是偏好设置的例子  这是一个
developer options. Here's a bunch of preferences. This is an example of
CheckBox型设置  这是一个List列表型设置
a CheckBoxPreference. This is an example of a ListPreference where you
你可以在这里看到不同的RadioButton控件选项  每次用户改变设置
have different RadioButton options here. Once the user changes the setting,
就会在默认的SharedPreferences文件中保存相应的值  这样我们就保存了key-value的键值对
it gets saved in the default SharedPreferences file. This stores a bunch of key
它们都是基础数据类型  让我们来举一个整型值设置的例子
value pairs of primitive data. An example integer preference could be how many
比如电子邮件的历史记录应该在本地保存多长时间  再比如说
days of e-mail history should be saved locally on the device. You could have
你可以将当前选择的账户和设备信息作为字符串存在SharedPreferences中
a string stored in SharedPreferences for what the currently selected account and
这样在任何时候  只要通过key值
device is. Then at any time you can fetch the value of this SharedPreferences,
你就可以从SharedPreferences中取得相应的value值
as long as you pass in the name of the key that you want.
另外你也可以在除设置功能以外的其它地方使用SharedPreferences功能
You can also use SharedPreferences outside the context of settings as well.
以上的信息都可以在开发者API指南中的怎样进行存储（Storage Options）一节
This information is located in the developer API guide, for
中找到  视频下面可以找到相应的链接
Storage Options, which is also linked below.